<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Organic Chemistry and Molecular Materials Research Laboratory</title>
    <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/tags/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Organic Chemistry and Molecular Materials Research Laboratory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/tags/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cover Arts</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/cover-arts/cover-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/cover-arts/cover-arts/</guid>
      <description>Some Works that have been selected as Cover Arts:&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2024/2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2024/2024/</guid>
      <description>Representiative Work: Our way to access [9]circulene&#xA;Negatively Curved Nanographenes&#xA;Cheung, K. M.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;submitted to&#xA;Molecular Nanographenes: Synthesis, Properties and Applications&#xA;Martin, N.; Nuckolls, C. (Ed.)&#xA;Wiley-VCH, Germany, 2024 Synthesis, Structures and Properties of Trioxa[9]circulene and Diepoxycyclononatrinaphthalene&#xA;Yang, D.; Cheung, K. M.; Gong, Q.; Zhang, L.; Qiao, L.; Chen, X.; Huang, Z. Miao, Q.*&#xA;Angewandte Chemie International Edition, 2024, 63, e202402756 Back Cover of Angewandte Chemie International Edition, 2024, 63, issue 23 An Eight-Membered Ring Formed by the Scholl Reaction of o-Quateraryls</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2023/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2023/2023/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Heptagon-embedded Nanographene (up to 6!) via pre-macrocyclization&#xA;Synthesis, Molecular Packing and Semiconductor Properties of V-Shaped N-Heteroacene Dimers&#xA;Xiong, Y.#; Gong, Q.#; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemistry – An Asian Journal, 2023, 18, e202300623 Selected as Very Important Paper An invited paper for the Joint Special Collection of Chemistry – An Asian Journal and The Chemical Record: Celebrating the 60th Anniversary of The Chinese University of Hong Kong Negatively Curved Molecular Nanocarbons Containing Multiple Heptagons Are Enabled by the Scholl Reactions of Macrocyclic Precursors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2022/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2022/2022/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Summary for the Scholl Reaction in Curved Aromatics (By us or other groups)&#xA;The Scholl Reaction as a Powerful Tool for Synthesis of Curved Polycyclic Aromatics&#xA;Zhang, Y.; Pun, S. H.; Miao, Q.* Chemical Reviews, 2022, 122, 14554–14593 An invited review A Highly Cited Paper identified by the Essential Science Indicators (ESI) Robust Radical Cations of Hexabenzoperylene Exhibiting High Conductivity and Enabling an Organic Nonvolatile Optoelectronic Memory&#xA;Wang, Y.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2021/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2021/2021/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Finished the mission of conquering All Carbon Nanobelt using Scholl Reaction!&#xA;Carbazole-Fused Polycyclic Aromatics Enabled by Regioselective Scholl Reactions&#xA;Zhao, M.; Pun, S. H.; Gong, Q.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Angewandte Chemie International Edition, 2021, 60, 24124–24130 Design, Synthesis and Hydrogen Bonding of B3N6-[4]Triangulene&#xA;Zhao, M.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Angewandte Chemie International Edition, 2021, 60, 21289-21294 Rearrangements Come to Scholl&#xA;Miao, Q.*&#xA;Nature Reviews Chemistry, 2021, 5, 602–603 An invited article of News &amp;amp; Views towards:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2020/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2020/2020/</guid>
      <description>Representative Works: Our first Attempts on Zig-Zag Carbon Nanobelt.&#xA;Recent Advances and Attempts in Synthesis of Conjugated Nanobelts&#xA;Chen, H.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Journal of Physical Organic Chemistry, 2020, e4145 An invited review Cover of Journal of Physical Organic Chemistry, Volume 33, Issue 12 From Polycyclic Arenes Containing Eight-Membered Rings to Negatively Curved Nanocarbons: Progress and Outlook&#xA;从含有八元环的稠环芳烃到具有负曲率的碳纳米结构：进展与展望&#xA;Miao, Q.*; Yang, D.&#xA;缪谦*、杨代月&#xA;Progress in Chemistry, 2020, 32, 1835–1845&#xA;化学进展，2020, 32, 1835–1845 An invited paper for the Special Issue to celebrate Professor Henry N.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2019/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2019/2019/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: First Chiral Carbon Nanobelt !, as well as a new Armchair Carbon Nanobelt, all done by Scholl Reaction.&#xA;A Tetraazapentacene-Pyrene Belt: Toward Synthesis of N-Doped Zigzag Carbon Nanobelts&#xA;Wang, J.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Organic Letters, 2019, 21, 10120−10124 Highlighted by Synfacts, 2020, 16, 279 Synthesis, Structures and Properties of Heptabenzo[7]circulene and Octabenzo[8]circulene&#xA;Pun, S. H.; Wang, Y.; Chu, M.; Chan, C. K.; Li, Y.; Liu, Z.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Journal of the American Chemical Society, 2019, 141, 9680–9686 A Ketone-Functionalized Aromatic Saddle as a Potential Building Block for Negatively Curved Carbon Nanobelts</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2018</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2018/2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2018/2018/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Highest mobility achieved n-type Organic Semiconductor.&#xA;Stable and Efficient 3D-2D Perovskite-Perovskite Planar Heterojunction Solar Cell without Organic Hole Transport Layer&#xA;Zhang, T.; Long, M.; Qin, M.; Lu, X.; Chen, S.; Xie, F.; Gong, L.; Chen, J.; Chu, M.; Miao, Q.; Chen, Z.; Xu, W.; Liu, P.; Xie, W.*; Xu, J.*&#xA;Joule, 2018, 2, 2706–2721&#xA;(Collaboration with Prof. Jianbin Xu&amp;rsquo;s Group) A Trefoil Macrocycle Synthesized by 3-Fold Benzannulation&#xA;Yang, X.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2017</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2017/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2017/2017/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: First eight-membered ring embedded nanographene by our group!&#xA;A Twisted Nanographene Consisting of 96 Carbon Atoms&#xA;Cheung, K. Y.; Chan, C. K.; Liu, Z.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Angewandte Chemie International Edition, 2017, 56, 9003–9007 Selected as a Hot Paper Front cover of Angewandte Chemie International Edition 2017, volume 56, issue 31 N-Phenylated N-Heteroacenes: Synthesis, Structures and Properties&#xA;Gu, X.; Shan, B.; He, Z.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;ChemPlusChem, 2017, 82, 1034–1038 An invited paper for the Special Issue: Novel Aromatics: From Synthesis to Applications Synthesis, Structure and Properties of Tetrabenzo[7]circulene</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2016</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2016/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2016/2016/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Pushing the limit of n-type organic semiconductor, observing band-like charge transport.&#xA;Polycyclic Arenes and Heteroarenes: Synthesis, Properties, and Applications&#xA;Miao, Q. (Ed.)&#xA;Wiley-VCH, Weinheim, Germany, 2016.&#xA;Chapter 4: Polycyclic Arenes Containing Seven-Membered Carbocycles&#xA;Cheung, K. Y.; Miao, Q.* Twisted Polycyclic Arenes from Diphenyltetranaphthylbenzenes by Controlling the Scholl Reaction with Substituents&#xA;Yang, Y.; Yuan, L.; Shan, B.; Liu, Z.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemistry – A European Journal, 2016, 22, 18620–18627 Benzo[4,5]cyclohepta[1,2-b]fluorene: an Isomeric Motif for Pentacene Containing Linearly Fused Five-, Six- and Seven-membered Rings</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2015</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2015/2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2015/2015/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: 2 heptagons in 1 nanographene, we can finally see how more heptagons shape the structure of nanographene.&#xA;Synthesis, Molecular Packing and Thin Film Transistors of Dibenzo[a,m]rubicenes&#xA;Gu, X.; Xu, X.; Li, H.; Liu, Z.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Journal of the American Chemical Society, 2015, 137, 16203–16208 Highlighted by Synfacts, 2016, 12, 258 Solution-Processed Ambipolar Organic Thin Film Transistors by Blending p- and n-Type Semiconductors: Solid Solution versus Microphase Separation</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2014</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2014/2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2014/2014/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: A pentacene analogue with 2 heptagons, Also a great p-type semiconductor.&#xA;Self-Assembled Monolayers of Cyclohexyl-Terminated Phosphonic Acids as a General Dielectric Surface for High-Performance Organic Thin-Film Transistors&#xA;Liu, D.; He, Z.; Su, Y.; Diao, Y.; Mannsfeld, S. C. B.; Bao, Z.; Xu, J. Miao, Q.*&#xA;Advanced Materials, 2014, 26, 7190–7196 Restriction of Intramolecular Motions: the General Mechanism behind Aggregation-Induced Emission&#xA;Leung, N. L. C.; Xie, N.; Yuan, W.; Liu, Y.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2013</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2013/2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2013/2013/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: An important progress of our group&amp;rsquo;s results on SAM layers for improved semiconductor performance.&#xA;Conjugated Macrocycles of Phenanthrene: a New Segment of [6,6]-Carbon Nanotube and Solution-Processed Organic Semiconductors&#xA;He, Z.; Xu, X.; Zheng, X.; Ming, T.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemical Science, 2013, 4, 4525-4531 Revisiting Zethrene: Synthesis, Reactivity and Semiconductor Property&#xA;Shan, L.; Liang, Z.; Xu, X.; Tang, Q.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemical Science, 2013, 4, 3294-3297 Highlighted by Synfacts, 2013, 9, 0953 Self-Assembled Monolayers of Phosphonic Acids with Enhanced Surface Energy for High-Performance Solution-Processed N-Channel Organic Thin Film Transistors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2012</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2012/2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2012/2012/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Starting the journey of negatively curved nanographene and Hexabenzoperylene (HBP), which are pivotal for our group&amp;rsquo;s research.&#xA;High-Quality Large-Area Graphene from Dehydrogenated Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbons&#xA;Wan, X.; Chen, K.; Liu, D.; Chen, J.; Miao, Q.; Xu, J.*&#xA;Chemistry of Materials, 2012, 24, 3906-3915.&#xA;(Collaboration with Prof. Jianbin Xu&amp;rsquo;s Group) Curved Polycyclic Aromatic Molecules that Are π-Isoelectronic to Hexabenzocoronene&#xA;Luo, J.; Xu, X.; Mao, R. Miao, Q.*&#xA;Journal of the American Chemical Society, 2012, 134, 13796-13803 Highly Electron-Deficient Hexaazapentacenes and Their Dihydro Precursors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2011</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2011/2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2011/2011/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Starting the journey of Tetraazapentacene(TAP), our star OFET molecule.&#xA;The Position of Nitrogen in N-Heteropentacenes Matters&#xA;Liang, Z.; Tang, Q.; Mao, R.; Liu D.; Xu, J.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Advanced Materials, 2011, 23, 5514-5518 Vapochromic and Semiconducting Solids of a Bifunctional Hydrocarbon&#xA;Xia, H.; Liu, D.; Song, K.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemical Science, 2011, 2, 2402-2406 Switching of Non-Helical Overcrowded Tetrabenzoheptafulvalene Derivatives&#xA;Luo, J.; Song, K.; Gu, F.; Miao, Q.*</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2008-2010</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2008-2010/2008-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/2008-2010/2008-2010/</guid>
      <description>Representative Work: Our group&amp;rsquo;s solution to the long-lasting questions of growing crystalline rubrene thin film.&#xA;N-Type Organic Semiconductors Based on π-Deficient Pentacenequinones: Synthesis, Electronic Structures, Molecular Packing and Thin Film Transistors&#xA;Liang, Z.; Tang, Q.; Liu, J.; Li, J.; Yan, F.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemistry of Materials, 2010, 22, 6438-6443 N-Heteroquinones: Quadruple Weak Hydrogen Bonds and N-Channel Transistors&#xA;Tang, Q.; Liang, Z.; Liu, J.; Xu, J.; Miao, Q.*&#xA;Chemical Communications, 2010, 46, 2977-2979 Induced Crystallization of Rubrene in Thin Film Transistors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before CUHK</title>
      <link>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/beforecuhk/beforecuhk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaogroupcuhk.github.io/publications/beforecuhk/beforecuhk/</guid>
      <description>Hexathiapentacene: Structure, Molecular Packing and Thin-Film Transistors&#xA;Briseno, A.L.; Miao, Q.; Ling, M.-M.; Reese, C.; Meng, H.*; Bao, Z.*; Wudl, F.*&#xA;Journal of the American Chemical Society, 2006, 128, 15576-15577 Chemical Complementarity in the Contacts for Nanoscale Organic Field-Effect Transistors&#xA;Tulevski, G.S.; Miao, Q.; Afzali, A.; Graham, T.; Kagan C.*; Nuckolls, C.*&#xA;Journal of the American Chemical Society, 2006, 128, 1788-1789 Organization of Acenes with a Cruciform Assembly Motif</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
